# Sarah Skillen

## Software Engineer

kjskillen@gmail.com 360-773-7586 **Personal website** 







Software engineer who enjoys research, planning, design, implementing, debugging, and testing all while using the agile method and working remotely. A strong team player who can quickly learn and apply new technologies to organizations by collaborating and optimizing processes. Able to think fast to come up with a solution to solve any issue encountered. Learning is the key to life!

#### **EDUCATION**

### **Alchemy Code lab** Diploma | SEPT 2020 - MAR 2021

An intensive remote program diving into full stack lavaScript applications.

## **Career Institute Tennessee** Cosmetology | JUNE 2007 - JUNE 2008

Certificated and licensed in cosmetology

## PROFESSIONAL HISTORY

## Alchemy Code Lab // 2021 **Software Engineer Teacher Assistant Executive //OCT 2021 - PRESENT**

Responsible for planning and implementation of materials for the new teacher assistants. Provided remote instructional support and mentorship for students learning complex JavaScript concepts, including debugging, analyzing code, critical and constructive feedback, and PR reviews. Planned and hosted an inner Alchemy Hackathon for all students who had different skill levels for a week-long sprint creating a Monster theme application. Maintain and or make the learning material for the students to complete

#### // SEPT 2021 - OCT 2021

Jack of all trades mentor and assist students who are learning complex JavaScript remotely. Grade and assist new students beginning the program and updating markdown files on how to setup your os system to make it more understandable for the beginner. ALso help the lead instructor in class, with debugging, writing and understanding the code by taking validation steps throughout the entire program.

## **Software Engineer Student Teacher** // MAR 2021 - SEPT 2021

Mentor and assist students remotely who are learning complex concepts in Javascript, React, Node and PostgreSQL, completing daily PR reviews and assisting with debugging and clarification.

#### Sport Clip // 2012-2020

#### Lead Stylist // OCT 2018 - OCT 2020

Focused on training new hires to fulfill positions with a qualified knowledge on how to treat every customer while adhering to the rules and procedures of the company. With this position I had to think on my feet and find solutions that worked best for both participants.

#### Stylist // OCT 2012 - OCT 2018

Leaned into team collaboration and communication to offer clients the best service.

#### **TECH SKILLS**

#### Languages JavaScript HTML CSS **PYTHON**

## **Frameworks** React Redux Node

#### Supabase Deployment Heroku Express GitHubPages

Testing

**Database** 

PostgreSQL

lest

QUnit

## **Licenses and Certifications**

Responsive Web Design JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures Learning React.js React.js Essential Training Node.js Essential Training Vue.js Testing and Debugging Learning SQL Programming **SQL Essential Training** 

#### **PROJECTS**

## **Oregon Trail** JavaScript | HTML | CSS

GIT

This was a fun and cool remake of the classic Oregon Trail in Vanilla lavaScript.

This was performed working remotely in a one week sprint. My main contribution was creating a health function that added and subtracted depending on what path the user chose. Leveraged higher order components to maximize component reusability.

## **Karaoke Roulette** Node | Express | SQL | JavaScript

GIT

**DEPLOYED** 

Have fun while also being able to social distance with our karaoke app. During this remote sprint, my main contribution was pulling the team together and guiding the developers to work in teams. I also worked in the back end of the app ending up in the front end helping to create a wonderful app. Then a teammate and I pair-programmed an API for storing data from a scraped file and created a matching algorithm to connect our data structure to a third-party API.

## **Bloom Financial** Node|Express|SQL| React

GIT **DEPLOYED** 

Thinking about investing? Try our site with paper trading until you're ready to use your own money.

While working remotely during a ten day sprint, my team accomplished an amazing app that incorporates oAuth from Alpaca trade api to allow the user to execute paper trades, look at the stock news and a graph that is able to show multiple companies to compare and help you decide what companies to invest in. My main contribution was leading my team to complete tasks while I incorporated the oAuth for the user.